RIKIYA TAKEHI

rikiyat.github.io

rikiya.takehi@fuji.waseda.jp

Maryland, USA

github.com/rikiyat

SUMMARY

I am a 3rd-year undergraduate student in Waseda University, Japan; taking a year off. Currently, I am a guest researcher at NIST in the US, working with Prof. Ian Soboroff and conducting research mainly on IR. I am also remotely supervised by Yuta Saito of Cornell Univ. in Prof. Thorsten Joachims Lab, working on counterfactual learning and fairness in rankings. My research interest widely orbits around information retrieval and machine learning, particularly evaluation, fairness, search, recommendation, and rankings.

EDUCATION

4/2021 - Present Waseda University - Major in Computer Science Cumulative GPA: 3.87, Major GPA: 3.97 (WES-scale)

Tokyo, Japan

4/2018 - 3/2021 Waseda University Honjo Senior High School

Saitama, Japan

International School of Geneva 1/2009 - 3/2018

Geneva, Switzerland

EXPERIENCE

10/2023 - Present Guest Researcher, NIST - National Institute of Standards and Technology

Maryland, USA

- · Conducting research in the retrieval group with **Prof. Ian Soboroff**.
- · Working broadly on IR: metadata, evaluation and fair division.

remote

9/2023 - Present Research Intern, Hakuhodo Tech. Inc. / Negocia Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

Tackling a research on off-policy learning in collaboration with advertising companies.

remote

7/2023 - Present *Research Intern*, Hanjukukaso Inc.

Tokvo, Japan

- Remotely supervised by Yuta Saito (PhD student at Joachims Lab, Cornell Univ.)
- Working on fair ranking and counterfactual learning.

now on leave

2/2023 - 8/2023 Student Researcher, Sakai Lab - Waseda Univ.

Tokyo, Japan

Supervised by Prof. Tetsuya Sakai return in 10/2024

Researched and published a study on evaluation of conversational systems.

PUBLICATIONS

1. Rikiya Takehi, Akihisa Watanabe, and Tetsuya Sakai. 2023. Open-Domain Dialogue Quality Evaluation: Deriving Nuggetlevel Scores from Turn-level Scores In Proceedings of the Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval in the Asia Pacific Region (SIGIR AP '23). (acceptance rate = 36%) code | poster | slides | proceedings

LANGUAGES

Japanese - native, English - fluent (TOEFL iBT: 110), French - fluent (CEFR B2)